

# **Azad Mamiyev**

# Android Developer

azad.mamiyev.1998@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/azadmamiyev/ https://github.com/siftoshka

#### **PROFILE**

An Android Developer with 4 years of experience in developing, designing, and maintaining Android apps in multiple industries such as product tech companies, startups, and consulting agencies. Experienced in delivering features via A/B Testing, building Bitrise pipelines, writing tests, refactoring, and optimizing existing code.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Mobile Platform Developer, Cookpad &

Aug 2022 - Jul 2023

• Migrated a flow of onboarding screens from XML Views to Jetpack Compose.

Bristol, United Kingdom

- Working on building, editing, and optimizing Bitrise pipelines
- Covered features with unit, integration, and E2E tests
- Assisting iOS Engineers with migration to use generated paths using CreateAPI
- Exoplayer improvements (Better Buffering, Audio, New Features) by releasing via A/B testing. The wait time for video buffering decreased by 3 times.
- Release manager responsibilities: Releasing updates, Monitoring Crashlytics

#### **Android Developer**, ByAllMeans &

Aug 2020 - Jul 2022 Prague, Czech Republic

- Developed chat-related features with reactions
- Actively participated in product management, design & QA team meetings
- Implemented Google Play Billing Library
- Maintained the existing project with improvements to user experience

#### Intern Android Developer, CRBN Tech &

May 2019 - Aug 2019

• Developed a custom app integrating QR Code Reader and Music Player

Baku, Azerbaijan

• Partnered with peers to create an outstanding user experience

#### **EDUCATION**

**MSc.**, **Web & Software Engineering**, Czech Technical University in Prague *⊘* 

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

• Experienced in genetic algorithms and management information systems.

Prague, Czech Republic

• Well-versed in patterns, user interface design, and networking.

**BSc., Computer Science,** Azerbaijan State Oil and Industry University &

• Gained experience working on group projects

Sep 2015 - Jun 2019 Baku, Azerbaijan

#### **SKILLS**

Kotlin, Java, Swift, Jetpack Compose, Kotlin Flow and Coroutines, RxJava, Rest API, GraphQL, OkHttp, OpenAPI, Retrofit, Jetpack Libraries, Firebase Tools, SqlDelight, Koin, Dagger Hilt, Timber, jUnit, Espresso, Kaspresso, Mockito

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### **Habitube**, Movie Library App ⊘

- Successfully facilitated seamless migration from legacy technologies (Java, RxJava, XML Views) to modern development technologies (Kotlin, Coroutines, Compose) for end users
- Designed elegant and user-friendly interfaces using Figma

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English Turkish** Russian Azerbaijani Fluent (IELTS B2) Limited Native Native